Finding Aid for Richard Charles Boys papers, 1942-1964
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Richard Charles Boys papers 1942-1964
Boys, Richard Charles, 1912-
1 linear feet
85822 Aa 2
Professor of English at the University of Michigan. Correspondence concerning his work at the University of Michigan; letters from former students describing their World War II experiences; and papers concerning his organizational and University activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Professor Richard C. Boys (donor no. 5631 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Richard C. Boys was born Nov. 12, 1912, in Kalamazoo, Mich. He attended the University College of Southwest England (Exeter), 1930-31, and received a bachelor of arts degree from Harvard College in 1935, and a doctor of philosophy degree from the Johns Hopkins University in 1939. He joined the U-M faculty in 1939 with the rank of instructor, becoming assistant professor of English in 1952, and professor of English in 1958. His field of interest was 18th century English literature.
In 1948, he received the Henry Russel Award, which is given to a junior faculty member for distinguished teaching and service to the University. He was the author of Sir Richard Blackmore and the Wits (1949) and Studies in the Literature of the Augustan Age (1952).
He was a member of the Modern Language Association, Modern Humanities Research Association, U-M Research Club, and Johnson Society of Middle West. He died June 19, 1975.
The collection is arranged into two series: Correspondence and Topical and University Activities. The correspondence includes a file of letters from former students describing their World War II experiences. There is also a subseries of professional correspondence from 1947 to 1964. This subseries is arranged alphabetically and includes letters from such personages as Langston Hughes, Victor G. Reuther, Elmer Rice, and William W. Whitehouse. The Topical and University Activities subseries relates to Boys varied interests, such as the Art Cinema League, the Faculty Club, and the American Association of University Professors.
Subjects:
American Association of University Professors. University of Michigan Chapter.; Art Cinema League (University of Michigan); Boys, Richard C. (Richard Charles), 1912-1975; University of Michigan. Dept. of English Language and Literature.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Faculty Club (University of Michigan); University of Michigan. Summer Session.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Boys, Richard C. (Richard Charles), 1912-1975
Contributors:
Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967.; Reuther, Victor G. (Victor George), 1912-2004; Rice, Elmer, 1892-1967.; Whitehouse, William Whitcomb, 1891-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - World War II Correspondence
    - November-December 1942 (Box 1)
    - January-June 1943 (Box 1)
    - June-December 1943 (Box 1)
    - 1944 (Box 1)
  - Professional Correspondence 1947-1964
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 1)
    - A (Box 1)
    - B (Box 1)
    - C (Box 1)
    - D-E (Box 1)
    - F-G (Box 1)
    - H (Box 1)
    - J (Box 1)
    - K (Box 1)
    - L (Box 1)
    - M (Box 1)
    - 0 (Box 1)
    - P-Q (Box 1)
    - R (Box 1)
    - S (Box 1)
    - T (Box 1)
    - W (Box 1)
- Topical and University Activities
  - American Association of University Professors
    - Correspondence 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous papers 1947-1948 (Box 1)
  - Art Cinema League
    - Miscellanea 1948-1950 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, rules and policy 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1948-1950 (Box 1)
  - Arthur Case festschrift
    - Miscellaneous papers 1951 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Bibliography 1959-1962 of Richard C. Boys (Box 1)
  - Censorship 1947 (Box 1)
  - Dramatic Arts Center 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Faculty Club subcommittee
    - Reports and minutes 1960-1965 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence undated, 1960-1968 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous papers 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Haven and Mason Hall dedication 1952 papers (Box 1)
  - Henry Russel Award undated, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Parodies (Box 1)
  - Poems (Box 1)
  - Quadrangle 1949-1953 miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
  - Quarto, miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
  - Research Club 1955-1964 (Box 1)
  - Review, Mildred Walker "Unless the Wind Turns" (Box 1)
  - Summer session lecture series
    - Modern views of man and society 1952 (Box 1)
    - The popular arts in America 1953 (Box 1)
    - Patterns of American culture: contributions of the Negro 1956 (Box 1)
    - Social implications of economic change 1960 (Box 1)
    - American youth 1962 (Box 1)
    - Where we stand: a review of the American position on critical issues 1963 (Box 1)
    - The American Negro in transition 1964 (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson fellowship 1959-1963 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
  - Photographic portrait, 1948 (Box 1)